--==CMCT團隊榮譽出品==--
字幕調校:空石   影片壓制:hanksking
招募Q號:76846146
片名: 血色將至
不!
No!
找到她了 找到她了...
There she is. There she is.
終於找到了
There she is.
新墨西哥 恩格爾: 渣化試金銀法
女士們先生們
Ladies and gentlemen,
我穿越了半個州
I've traveled over half our state...
今晚來到這裏
to be here tonight.
我本該早些過來
I couldn't get away sooner...
但由於我在野狼山的新油井剛開始出油
because my new well was coming in
有些事要安排 一時間脫不開身
at Coyote Hills and I had to see about it.
那口井現在的出油量是兩千桶...
That well is now flowing at 2,000 barrels
每周都能給我帶來五千美金收入
and it's paying me an income of $5,000 a week.
我在別處還有兩支勘探隊
I have two others drillingand...
在羚羊谷有十六口產油井
I have 16 producing at Antelope,
所以說 先生們 女士們
so, ladies and gentlemen,
如果我自稱是一名油礦主 你們應該不會反對
if I say I'm an oilman, you will agree.
你們現在面對的機會絕佳...
Now, you have a great chance here,
但別忘了 如果疏忽大意
but bear in mind you could...
到頭來可能會一無所獲
lose it all if you're not careful.
也許有很多人在想...
Out of all men that beg for...
租你們的地 鑽井探油
a chance to drill your lots,
但20個人裏面 可能只有一個是油礦主
maybe one in twenty will be oilmen.
其餘的傢伙都是些投機分子
The rest will be speculators,
他們只想當礦主租地生意的中介人
that's men trying to get between you and the oilmen
將應屬於你們的部分財富
to get some of the money that ought,
攫為己有
by rights, come to you.
即便你們找到個...
Even if you find one that...
有錢又肯鑽井的主
has money and means to drill,
多半是個對鑽探一無所知的門外漢
he'll maybe know nothing about drilling.
這種人通常會把項目轉托給承包商
He'll have to hire the job out on contract,
你們的命運也押在了承包商手上...
and then you're depending on a contractor,
而承包商往往應付一下就早早收工
who'll rush the job through
用省出的時間...
so he can get another contract...
換新的一份承包合同
just as quick as he can.
我們這一行的規則就是如此
This is the way that this works.
- 那你肯給我們多少? - 我們在浪費時間
- What is your offer? - We're wasting time.
請安靜!
Please!
我親自負責鑽探...
I do my own drilling.
凡是為我工作的 只有我一個老闆
And the men that work for me, work for me,
每個工人我都瞭如指掌
and they are men I know.
我會把辦公室搬到鑽探現場
I make it my business to be there...
實地視察手下的工作
and to see their work.
我的人不會笨到把工具掉到井裏
I don't lose my tools in the hole...
然後再花幾個月在摸找工具上面
and spend months fishing for them.
也不會愚蠢地鑿穿固井層
I don't botch the cementing off
白白讓滲水毀了整口油井
and let water in the hole and ruin the whole lease.
我是一個家庭觀念很重的男人
I'm a family man.
把鑽井開油當成家族產業在做
I run a family business.
這是我的兒子兼合夥人H.W. 普萊維
This is my son and my partner, H.W. Plainview.
我們的理念是 大伙在一起就是一家人
We offer you the bond of family that...
雖然很少有油礦主能認同這種理念
very few oilmen can understand.
有一點我與其他同行都不一樣 我打算在長期采油
I'm fixed like no other company in this field
因為我的野狼山油井...
and that's because my Coyote Hills...
已開始出油
well has just come in.
我擁有成套的鑽探工具可隨時投入工作
I have a string of tools all ready to put to work.
我在別處的鑽井設備可立即裝車
I can load a rig onto trucks...
一周內就能運達這裏
and have them here in a week.
我有許多貿易夥伴
I have business connections,
能搞到搭建井架的木料
so I can get the lumber for the derricks.
只有靠朋友辦事才會有這種速度
Such things go by friendship in a rush like this.
所以我才敢在這兒和你們拍板 不僅可以立即開工
And this is why I can guarantee to start drilling
還能拿出充足的資金以證明我所言非虛
and to put up the cash to back my word.
女士們先生們 我向你們保證
I assure you, ladies and gentlemen,
其他人不管說得如何天花亂墜
no matter what the others promise to do,
當萬事俱備 只等開工的時候 他們就一個個地不見人影了
when it comes to the showdown, they won't be there.
坐下! 坐下 你不能...
Sit down! Sit down, you have no right...
讓我們談談最重要的話題
Let us discuss what the man has to say.
普雷斯科特 你相信他麼?
Prescott, do you trust this man?
讓我們談談最重要的話題
Let's discuss what he has to say.
他說的在理
There's logic to what he's saying.
他怎麼知道? 那是我的地!
How does he know? My lot is there!
他說兩到三年 也許是十年!
Two or three years, it could be ten years!
我們會到頭來一場空!
We gain nothing by losing our heads!
可他剛開了一口油井!
Look at that well out there!
沒人會一場空
Nobody's losing their heads.
你在這兒又沒生意!
You have no business being here!
讓那個女的坐好 先生!
Sit that woman down, sir!
你坐下
You can sit down.
普萊維先生! 請留步 普萊維先生
Mr. Plainview! Please, Mr. Plainview.
不 普萊維先生 你要去哪兒?
No, Mr. Plainview! No, where are you going?
謝你好意 但我不想簽約了
I don't need the lease. Thank you.
但我們需要你!
But we need you.
不同的意見太多了 耽誤你時間了
Too much confusion. Thank you for your time.
不不不 我們沒有不同意見
No, no, there's no confusion.
我不會在租約上簽字的...
I wouldn't take the lease...
即使現在把開採權白送給我
if you gave it to me as a gift.
班克塞先生 我不想浪費您的時間
Mr. Bankside, I'm not going to waste your time.
希望您也別...
I'd certainly appreciate it...
浪費我的時間
if you didn't waste mine.
如果與我簽了合同
Now, if you wish to sign with me,
十天內就可以開始鑽井
we can have a well drilling within 10 days.
您的土地位於...
Your lot is further north...
出油點的北面較遠處
from the discovery well up here.
這意味著可能要挖得更深才能見油
That means we'll probably have to dig deeper.
如果不出在下所料...
And if there's as much oil here as I think there is,
在您那兒找油會更加困難一些
it'll be harder to reach,
但只要找到油 開採不成問題
but once we find it, we can take it right out.
我們必須得加快行動
We have to act quickly,
否則過不多久這片地區的石油就會被開採殆盡的
because very soon these fields will be dry.
希望你們快做決定
I need you to know what you want to do.
由於距離石油發現點較遠...
Now because of the distance from the discovery well,
你的收益分成...
I'll pay you a smaller royalty...
將比預計的少一些
than you'd get down there
但我願多付您...
but I'm prepared to give you...
一千美元作征地補償
a $1,000 bonus on your lot.
你說的收益分成是多少?
What kind of royalty are you talking about?
六分之一
One-sixth,
外加十天內開工保證
plus a guarantee to start drilling within 10 days.
沒有比這更公道的價錢了
Now, that's something you won't find anywhere else.
夫人 你的孩子幾歲了?
What age are your children, ma'am?
一個十歲 另一個十二
Ten and twelve.
我有個問題 普萊維先生. 您的夫人呢?
Mr. Plainview, a question, sir. Where is your wife?
班克賽夫人 她死於難產
She died in childbirth, Mrs. Bankside.
現在只剩我們父子兩個了
So it's just me and my son now.
老闆 出油了!
It's coming in, boss!
聽這聲音!
Hear it?
普萊維先生?
Mr. Plainview?
哪位?
Yes?
您就是丹尼爾·普萊維?
Are you Daniel Plainview?
是我
Yes.
能為你效勞麼?
What can I do for you?
您在找石油?
You look for oil.
沒錯
That's right.
如果一個地方有油 您願為此付多少錢?
What do you pay for a place that has it?
- 要看情況了 - 看哪些情況?
- Well, that depends. - What does it depend on?
有許多因素
On a lot of things.
如果我知道哪塊地方有油
If I told you I knew a place that had oil...
而且那兒的地價又很便宜
where land could be bought cheaply,
您認為這個情報值多少錢?
what do you think that would be worth?
你得讓我先瞭解你都知道些什麼
I think that you should let me know what you know
然後我們再慢慢談
and then we'll try and work something out.
- 我能坐下麼? - 請坐吧
- Can I sit down? - Please.
請問您是哪個教派的?
What church do you belong to?
我麼...
I...
各種信仰我都不排斥
I enjoy all faiths.
也沒有特別確定的教派
I don't belong to one church in particular.
所有教派我都喜歡 我熱愛一切
I like them all. I like everything.
你從哪兒來?
Where are you from?
我一會兒告訴你
That would be telling you.
這也是我要賣給你的情報
That's what I want to sell you.
你在信號山這兒幹什麼工作?
What are you doing in Signal Hill?
我們那兒的油 多得都滲出地面了
We have oil, and it seeps through the ground.
想知道在哪兒麼? 付點錢給我吧
Do you want to pay me to know where it is?
光是地表冒油...
Just 'cause there's something on the ground
並不代表地底下有油
doesn't mean there's anything beneath it.
那為何標準石油公司要在我們那兒大肆收購土地?
Why did Standard Oil buy up land?
你說的地方在加利福尼亞?
Is it in California?
- 也許在 - 他們買下了多少土地?
- Maybe. - How much land did they buy?
希望你不是在懷疑我的智商 那樣我會好受一點
I'd like it better if you didn't think I was stupid.
你為什麼來找我?
Why did you come to me?
- 因為你在這兒的油井出油了 - 說的也是
- You just brought this well in. - That's right.
好吧 要不這樣 你給我500元
Yes, so just give me $500 in cash right now
我就把我知道的地方告訴你
and I'll tell you where it is.
年輕人 我的想法是這樣的
I'll tell you what I'll do, son.
我先給你100元...
I'll give you $100 now,
如果那塊地方真的有利可圖
and if it proves to be a promising lease,
我再獎給你1000元
then give you a $1,000 bonus.
先給我600元
Six hundred dollars.
為了幫助判斷 告訴我一件事情
Tell me one thing to help me decide.
你們那兒有些什麼?
What else have you got up there?
種著什麼作物?
What do you grow?
是一片大牧場 但大部分都是石地
We have a big ranch, but it's mostly rocks.
除了野草 種什麼都沒收成
Plant things. Nothing will grow but weeds.
你認為上面能長什麼?
What makes you think it's up?
那附近有硫磺或鹽堿礦麼?
Is there sulfur around? Or alkali deposits?
有鹽堿礦 硫磺是什麼我不清楚
Alkali nearby. I don't know sulfur.
那是你兒子?
Is that your son?
是的
Yes.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hi. - Hi.
- 請問您是哪位? - 我叫弗萊徹·哈密爾頓
- Who are you? - I'm Fletcher Hamilton.
很高興認識你 年輕人 你叫什麼名字?
Nice to meet you, son. What's your name?
你是幹什麼的?
What do you do?
我為普萊維先生工作
I work with Mr. Plainview.
這是500美金
Here's $500, son.
再說點有用的
You tell me something worth hearing,
這錢就給你
this money's yours.
我來自伊莎貝拉郡的...
I come from a town called...
小波士頓鎮
Little Boston in Isabella County.
我們在這裏
This is us, here.
這裏是小波士頓的馬刺火車站
Spur station here at Little Boston.
你們要找的是桑迪農場
The Sunday ranch is what you're looking for.
你們可以順著這條放羊道走
There's a sheep trail that takes you there.
出鎮往西走一英里 不是很遠的地方
It's a mile out of town headed west, not far.
穿過山腳下的...
Just through a small pass here...
這個小小隘口
near the base of the hills.
再經過一座教堂
You'll pass a church...
然後順著放羊道走就到了
and just follow the sheep trail.
- 標準石油公司買了哪幾塊地? - 這兒 還有這兒
- Where's Standard buying up? - Here and here.
- 你的家人姓桑迪? - 是的
- Your family name is Sunday, yes? - That's right.
家裏有幾口人?
How many's in your family?
我父母 幾個姐妹 還有我兄弟伊萊
My father and mother and sisters and my brother Eli.
- 你有幾個姐妹? - 兩個
- How many sisters do you have? - Two.
- 你叫什麼? - 保羅
- What's your name? - Paul.
你家人知道那兒...
Does any of your family know about...
附近有石油麼?
the oil that you say is there?
我不清楚
I don't know.
我叔叔常說附近有油
My uncle always said there was oil there,
但我不知道其他人聽說過沒有
but I don't know what they heard or what they think.
你們種些什麼?
What do you grow?
養了些羊 是個放羊的牧場
It's goats. It's a goat farm.
我說過 那兒除了野草什麼都不長
I told you, nothing grows but weeds.
- 有水源麼? - 有 但水質很咸
- Is there water? - It's salty.
打井取水 很少能取到不咸的水
You drill a well, it's hard not to get saltwater.
我敢肯定 那兒有石油
The oil is there. I'm telling you.
- 我要走了 那麼... - 今晚就住這裏好了
- I want to go now, so... - You can stay tonight.
不 我想走 我得離開這裏
No, I want to go now. I want to leave.
聽著 保羅
Listen, Paul.
假如我大老遠跑到那兒
If I travel all the way out there...
結果發現你是在說謊...
and I find that you've been lying to me,
我會抓到你
I'm going to find you...
讓你吐出更多的錢
and I'm going to take more than my money back.
你覺得這樣可以麼?
Is that all right with you?
- 可以 先生 - 那就這樣吧
- Yes, sir. - All right, then.
祝您好運 願主保佑你
Nice luck to you. God bless.
你也一樣 年輕人
And to you, young man.
- 有人過來了 - 謝謝 瑪麗
- There's someone coming. - Thank you, Mary.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Good evening. - Good evening.
我叫丹尼爾·普萊維 這是我兒子H.W
My name's Daniel Plainview. This is my son, H.W.
- 你們來打獵麼? - 來獵鵪鶉
- Are you hunting? - Hunting for quail.
先前聽別人說桑迪農場附近
We're told there might be a good place...
有塊地方適合露營
to camp up near the Sunday ranch.
這兒就是桑迪農場 你們可以在這裏露營
This is the Sunday ranch. You can camp here.
- 謝謝你 有水麼? - 有的
- Thank you. Do you have water? - Yes.
聽說這兒幾天前...
We heard there was an earthquake...
發生了地震
up here a few days ago.
- 是真的麼? - 是的
- Is that right? - Yes.
- 你家人好麼? - 他們都好 謝謝關心
- Your family? - Yeah, all fine. Thank you.
如果不介意 我們有羊奶
We have goat's milk, if you'd like.
那很好
That would be fine.
那麼
Now,
如果我們把帳篷紮在那兒
if we set our tent away over there,
就不會擋你們的路了
we'd be out of your way over there.
沒問題
That's fine.
露絲 來幫忙 帶點水過來
Ruth! Help these men and bring them some water.
不用! H.W你去
No! H.W.
普萊維先生 要不要現在來點羊奶?
Mr. Plainview, would you like that milk now?
好的 謝謝
That would be fine. Thank you.
瑪麗 拿點羊奶來
Mary! Bring them some milk.
我家人會幫你扎帳篷的
My family will help you set up your tent.
不用了 謝謝 我們一路上都是自己動手的
No, please. We set ourselves on this camping trip.
我們得自己紮營
We have to do the camping.
快點!
Hurry up!
- 有麵包麼? - 只有土豆
- Do you have bread? - We have potatoes.
土豆也可以 謝謝你
Potatoes would be nice, thank you.
我讓她們去把土豆煮好
I'll have them boil you up some potatoes.
沒關係 我們可以自己烤
That's all right. I thought maybe we'd make a fire.
我準備帶兒子一起生堆篝火
I wanted to work with my son on making a fire.
那好 我兒子伊萊會送柴火來的
All right. My son, Eli, will bring you some wood.
謝謝盛情款待 您是桑迪先生?
Thank you so much for your hospitality, Mr. Sunday.
- 是的 - 我們不會妨礙你們的
- Yes. - And we'll be out of your way.
- 只是來打鵪鶉的 - 好的
- We're just hunting for quail. - Yes.
- 很抱歉 麵包沒有了 - 不 沒關係
- I'm sorry we don't have any bread. - No, no, no.
這山頭種不了糧食
Corn doesn't fill out in the hills here.
到處都是石頭...
It's mostly rock.
連塊像樣的糧食地也沒有
We don't have room to raise the grain.
謝謝你 年輕的小姐
Thank you, young lady.
我叫伊萊
My name is Eli.
你就是伊萊·桑迪吧
Yes, you're Eli Sunday.
歡迎您來這兒
Welcome.
- H.W - 伊萊
- H.W. - Eli.
- 你們來獵鵪鶉? - 是的
- You're hunting quail? - That's right.
我們會送晚飯過來的
We will bring dinner.
謝謝 太感謝你們了
Thank you. Thank you so much.
爸爸!
Dad!
爸爸 看我的鞋子
Dad, look at my shoe.
這些石油是因為地震才冒出來的 我們走
That's earthquake oil. Set loose.
這麼說...
So...
怎麼說?
So?
這麼說的話...
So, so.
如果這底下藏著油 可以把它往海邊運
If there's anything here, we take it to the sea.
我們要做的就是建一條輸油管線
What we do is we build a pipeline...
終點是韋尼繆港或聖保拉
to Port Hueneme or Santa Paula,
總長大約100英里
it's about 100 miles,
然後把油賣給聯合石油公司 我們要做的就是這些
and we do a deal with Union Oil. This is what we do.
這樣就不需要鐵路了
Then we don't need the railroads...
也不必在貨運上花錢了
and their shipping costs anymore.
你明白嗎?
You see?
明白了
Yeah.
- 全都明白了? - 是的
- You see that? - Yeah.
然後我們就坐等收錢吧
Then we're making money.
真金白銀滾滾而來...
We're making the real money.
每個硬幣都落入我們的腰包
What we should be making. Not just...
無需再把錢浪費在運輸上了
Not just throwing it away on shipping costs.
不然的話 就剩不下幾個錢了
Otherwise, it's just mud.
我們要付給他們多少錢?
How much are we going to pay them?
哪個他們?
Who's that?
桑迪一家
The Sunday family.
我們不用石油的名義買
I'm not going to give them oil prices.
我們用鵪鶉的名義買
I'll give them quail prices.
佔用您幾分鐘時間
If we could take a few minutes,
有件事情很想...
there's something I'd very much...
和您談談
like to talk with you about.
孩兒他媽 把姑娘們帶出去
Mother, would you take the girls outside, please?
我喜歡直話直說
I believe in plain speaking, so...
您的農場很漂亮 我很喜歡獵鵪鶉
This is a beautiful ranch. I love hunting for quail.
你知道 我兒子身體不太好 他需要多呼吸新鮮空氣
My boy has been sick, you know. He needs fresh air.
看過的醫生都說 最好讓他生活在空氣清新的地方
Doctors all say he needs plentiful fresh air.
所以...
So,
你認為這塊地...
what would you say would be a...
賣多少錢合適 埃布爾?
fair price for this lot, Abel?
- 你要買下這地方? - 說得沒錯
- To buy this place? - That's right.
不急 慢慢想
Take a moment.
- 我不知道該賣多少 - 每英畝六美元
- I'm sorry. I don't know. - Six dollars an acre.
六美元? 謝謝你開價 伊萊
Six dollars? Thank you, Eli.
這幾年裝修農場花了不少錢
And then with the improvements to the ranch...
大概500美元的樣子...
over the years at $500...
我願出3700美元買下這片農場
I'd like to offer you $3,700 for this ranch.
- 一共3700美元 - 不行
- That's $3,700. - No.
伊萊 這個人是上帝派來的啊
The Lord has sent this man here, Eli.
是的 我也相信是上帝讓我來的
Yes, I believe He has.
我給你們的報價是3700美元
My offer to you is $3,700.
究竟是什麼讓你來這裏的 先生?
What is it that brought you here, sir?
是上蒼神意的指引
The Good Lord's guidance.
- 當然... - 我們的石油呢?
- Now, of course... - What about our oil?
除了神意之外 我們還得簽一份合同
within that we're going to develop a lease.
- 你說什麼? - 我們的石油呢?
- What's that? - What about our oil?
什麼石油?
What about it?
我們這兒有石油 應該值不少錢
We have oil here. That's worth something.
你能組織人鑽探麼?
Do you have someone who can drill for it?
- 你認為這兒有石油? - 我知道這兒有
- Do you think there's oil here? - I know there is.
要鑽探石油得花很多錢
It's very expensive to drill.
把油從地底下取出來是大工程
To get it up and out of the ground.
你之前有沒有試過自己開採?
You ever tried that before?
- 要花多少錢? - 很多錢
- How much is it? - Costly.
但是 這兒的油埋得很淺
Well, our oil sits right up on top of the ground.
我相信你看到的是滲油
I believe that's called seepage.
這並不代表
Doesn't necessarily mean...
下面藏著石油
there's anything underneath.
- 為此你準備出多少錢? - 我沒想過
- What would you give us for it? - I don't know.
- 這事你竟然沒想過? - 是的 沒錯
- Something you don't know. - That's right.
你想要多少 伊萊?
What would you like, Eli?
一萬美金
Ten thousand dollars.
為了什麼?
For what?
為了我的教堂
For my church.
說得不錯
That's good.
這是個好理由
That's a good one.
好罷...
Well...
如果我們決定在此開採石油
If we decide to drill for oil...
如果此地真能產油
and if the well begins to produce,
我會給你的教堂捐5000美元
I'll give your church a $5,000 signing bonus.
一萬美元
Ten thousand.
你想去找別人...
Do you want to find someone else...
來這裏鑽探麼? 伊萊?
that's going to come here and drill, Eli?
投入資金
Make the investment...
還要自己出工出力...
and do all the hard work that goes into it?
我大可以找一處別的農場
I can just as easily hunt for quail...
在那兒安安靜靜的獵鵪鶉
on another ranch as I can here, so...
但我也很樂意...
Though I'll happily be a supporter...
盡全力支持你的教堂
of your church for as long as I can.
前提是這兒真的有石油
For the bonus only.
假如真有油的話
Now, as it happens,
我倒是有些鑽探行當的熟人...
I do have some connections in the drilling business
到時候能幫我們做些采油的事情
who might help get us started.
你覺得怎麼樣 埃布爾?
How do you feel about this, Abel?
我沒意見 聽伊萊的就行
Yes. What Eli says.
好吧 那這樣 先簽幾份合同
Well, good! Let's draw up some contracts and let's.
我們一起試試看
Let's give it a try.
感謝你的協助 伊萊
Appreciate your help with this, Eli.
- 下午好 - 下午好
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon.
- 土地管理局? - 是的
- Real estate? - Yes.
我找您有事
Yes, I'd like to talk to you.
我想找幾塊地
I'm looking for some land.
我剛買了桑迪農場
I just bought the Sunday ranch.
然後...呃 能看下地圖麼?
And, well, where's the map?
桑迪農場後面的丘陵在哪兒?
Where are the hills behind the Sunday ranch?
在這兒 這塊土地屬於班迪
That's here. It's the Bandy tract.
一共六百多英畝
He has over 600 acres.
班迪 六百...
Bandy, 600.
那這塊地方呢?
What about this?
A.C·莫德 布羅基特 雷德利克 卡爾...
A.C. Maude, Blodget, Redlick, Carr.
- 地價多少? - 每英畝六美元
- What's it held at? - Six dollars an acre.
六美元...
Six.
這兒呢?
What about this?
是貝爾文的地 買下應該沒問題 我敢肯定
That's the Belvins, and that could be got, I'm sure.
這兒附近的土地都能買到手麼?
Can everything around here be got?
是的 肯定
Sure.
保羅·桑迪曾是我們的好朋友
Paul Sunday turned out to be a good friend of ours.
沒錯
That's right.
你快點過來吧
Well, you get here just as soon as you can.
叫弗雷德·英吉利一起來
Bring Fred English.
好 就這樣
Good enough.
謝謝你 師傅
Thank you, porter.
- H.W 你好麼? - 很好 您呢?
- H.W., how are you? - Fine, and you?
- 還不錯 你爸呢? - 他在裏面
- Pretty good. Where's your dad? - He's inside.
你們大老遠從希格諾山到這兒來...
You fellas are a long way from Signal Hill.
- 你好啊 普萊維 - 你好 吉恩
- Hello, Plainview. - Hello, Gene.
- 很高興見到你 - 你好查理
- Good to see you. - Charlie.
這是趕著去哪兒?
On your way somewhere else?
順路經過這裏 就下來看看
Passing through. Looking around.
- 你也在這兒 真奇怪啊 - 是啊 我也覺得奇怪
- Funny to see you. - Funny, isn't it?
你的人又在忙家族產業了
You boys are a regular family business.
你的人這次遲到了
You boys are a little late.
你發現了什麼?
What did you find?
一些有趣的東西
I found some interesting prospects.
聽說標準石油在此購地了麼?
Did you hear Standard bought up?
- 他們現在買的地皮大多在鎮子北面 - 我也聽人這麼說
- Mostly in the north, so far. - That's what I hear.
跟你說 吉恩
I'm gonna tell you, Gene,
如果你也想加入 從鎮東面開始吧...
if you're gonna make a play, look east.
早晚別人會來 我寧願那人是你
I'd rather it be you than someone else.
你腳下的這片土地已名花有主了
This mud around here has been taken.
身邊帶著個俏臉蛋
It must be easy when you have such a cute face
每天的陽光都燦爛啊
to carry around with you.
你想誇我兒子英俊?
Telling me how handsome my son is?
就算我是好了
Well, that I am.
真動聽 謝謝誇獎 祝你好運 吉恩
That's very nice. Thank you. Good luck, Gene.
- 多保重 - 聽我的話 去東面看看
- Take care. - Like I said, go east.
H.W
H.W.
如果你需要簽合同
I'll be your lawyer if...
我願當你的律師
you need to draw up a contract.
以免你上人家的當
Make sure you don't get swindled, boy.
你老爸賺的錢也該有你一半
Get half what your dad's making.
這裏怎麼樣?
How's that?
那些人在做什麼?
What are those men doing?
他們為我們工作
They're just guys that are working for us.
他們只是在這兒四處看看
They're just looking around.
我們能賺多少錢?
How much money can we make?
我不知道 要看情況了
I don't know. It depends.
一千美元?
One thousand dollars?
瑪麗說如果她不禱告
Mary said that her father beats her...
她爸會揍她
if she doesn't pray.
瑪麗 是那個最小的女兒?
Mary, she's the smaller one?
是的
Yes, she is.
- 人都到齊了? - 基本順利
- Everyone here? - Very successful.
但是...?
But?
只有一個人 他名下的地產尚無著落
There were a few vacant lots and one holdout.
- 誰? - 威廉·班迪
- Who? - William Bandy.
一共八塊地...他什麼來頭?
...eight. Who's he?
是個老頭 在此定居
He's an old man who homesteaded here.
他和孫子一起住
Lives with his grandson.
他有話要和你說
He said he'd like to speak with you.
他來了麼?
Is he here?
沒來 他希望你親自上門拜訪
No, he'd like you to come visit with him.
他想抬價?
He's boosting his price.
他說想和...
He said he'd like to speak...
買地的人談談
with whoever is doing the buying.
那就讓他等著吧 下次他自己會來的 我們走
Well, let him wait. He'll come around. Let's go.
女士們 先生們...
Ladies and gentlemen?
女士們 先生們
Ladies and gentlemen.
謝謝你們今晚能來到這兒
Thank you so much for visiting with us this evening.
我穿越了半個州
Now, I've traveled across half our state...
最後把目光投在這片土地上
to be here and to see about this land.
你們中有些可能已經聽說了...
Now, I daresay some of you might have heard
某些有關本人計劃的...
some of the more extravagant rumors...
無邊傳聞
about what my plans are,
我想在此親自道明事實的真相
so I just thought you'd like to hear it from me.
大家面對面 沒什麼神秘的
This is the face. It's no great mystery.
女士們先生們 我是一個油礦主
I'm an oilman, ladies and gentlemen,
我在本州有許多產業
I have numerous concerns spread across this state.
我的油井群...
I have many wells flowing at...
每日出產幾千桶原油
many thousand barrels per day,
因此我自認是一名油礦主
so I like to think of myself as an oilman.
作為一名油礦主
As an oilman, I hope that you'll forgive
我這人向來有話直說 請各位見諒
just good old-fashioned plain speaking.
這個行當對我來說
Now, this work that we do is...
是家族產業
very much a family enterprise.
我的好兒子H.W和我並肩作戰
I work side by side with my wonderful son, H. W.
你們中有些人
I think one or two of you...
可能見過他
might have met him already.
我還鼓勵手下...
And I encourage my men...
也將家人帶在身邊
to bring their families, as well.
當然 有家人陪伴
Of course, it makes for an ever so much...
生活也變得更有滋味
more rewarding life for them.
成家了就會有孩子 有孩子就該有教育
Family means children, and children means education.
所以不管我們在哪兒落腳
So, wherever we set up camp,
教育都是必不可少的
education is a necessity,
我也很樂意為孩子提供教育的機會
and we're just so happy to take care of that.
我要在小波士頓建一流的學校
So let's build a wonderful school in Little Boston.
孩子就是我們為之奮鬥的未來
These children are the future that we strive for,
他們理當擁有最好的東西
and so they should have the very best of things.
現在 我還要說一件事
Now, something else,
請恕我冒犯...
and please don't be insulted...
我要說的是麵包
if I speak about this. Bread.
讓我們談談麵包吧
Let's talk about bread.
我印象中 在這個偉大的國家裏
Now, to my mind, it's an abomination to consider
任何男人...
that any man,
女人或是小孩子 如果把一塊麵包當作奢侈品
woman, or child in this magnificent country of ours
將是多麼的可悲
should haveto look upon a loaf of bread as a luxury.
我們可在此地挖水井
We're going to dig water wells here,
有了淡水 就能灌溉
and water wells means irrigation.
有了灌溉 就能種糧食
Irrigation means cultivation.
那些曾經的不毛之地
We're going to raise crops here where...
將變成良田沃野
before it just simply wasn't possible.
等到收穫季節
You're going to have more grain...
糧食多得發愁
than you'll know what to do with,
你家的麵包會堆得...
and bread will be coming right...
淹過脖子 女士
out of your ears, ma'am.
修建道路 發展農業 提供就業 興辦教育...
New roads, agriculture, employment, education.
這只是我們建設計劃中的寥寥幾項而已
These are just a few of the things we can offer you,
女士們先生們 我向你們保證
and I assure you, ladies and gentlemen,
如果在這裏找到了石油...
that if we do find oil here,
我覺得此事為真的可能性很大
and I think there's a very good chance that we will,
你們不但能在此地繼續繁衍
this community of yours will not only survive,
這片家園還將更加興旺富強
it will flourish.
如果有什麼問題
I'd be happy to answer any questions...
儘管向我提... 什麼問題?
that you might have. Yes?
新辟的道路通往教堂麼?
Will the new road lead to the church?
教堂將會是新路的第一站
That'll be the first place that it leads.
謝謝你伊萊 還有問題麼?
Thank you, Eli. Anyone else?
那好 如果有其他疑惑 我會一直恭候大駕光臨
Well, if anything comes up, I'm pretty easy to find.
到時儘管來找我
You just come visit with me.
謝謝你們今晚的參與 晚安
Thank you so much for your time, and good night.
"這是我們的特權...
What a privilege to carry
"用祈禱向神祝願...
everything to God in prayer!
這是我們的特權..."
What a privilege to carry...
順著新路走就能到教堂了
Just follow the new road right to the church.
順著新路走就不會走錯
The new road will lead you there.
你好 兄弟 我叫伊萊
Hello, brother, my name is Eli.
第三啟示教會歡迎您光臨
The Church of the Third Revelation welcomes you.
第一啟示為摩西十誡；第二為耶穌臨世；
預言中還有第三次末日啟示 尚未發生
你好 兄弟 我叫伊萊
Hello, brother, my name is Eli.
第三啟示教會歡迎您光臨
The Church of the Third Revelation welcomes you.
順著新路走就能到教堂了
Just follow the new road right to the church.
"耶穌知道世人的罪
Jesus knows our every weakness
"真心祈禱向神懺悔
Take it to the Lord in prayer
"我們脆弱又疲憊
Are we weak and heavy-laden
"他人關切成累贅
Cumbered with a load of care?
"救世主給了我們安慰
Precious Savior still our refuge
真心祈禱向神懺悔..."
Take it to the Lord in prayer...
- 能和你說幾句麼 丹尼爾? - 可以 請進吧
- Daniel, may I speak with you? - Yes, come in.
等他們到了 我就帶過來
I'll bring them up when they arrive.
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
工作進展怎麼樣?
How is all the work coming?
都很順利
Everything's good.
- 所有工人都已就位? - 當然
- All the men are provided for? - Of course.
士氣好像很高昂啊
Spirits seem high.
需要我為你們做什麼嘛?
Is there anything that you need from me?
需要教會做什麼嗎?
Anything the church can do for you?
我想還沒有 謝謝你
I don't believe so. No. Thank you.
聽說你讓眾人明天到這兒集合...
I understand you've asked the people to gather
一起參加油井開工儀式
around and watch the well begin tomorrow.
- 有這回事麼? - 有這麼回事
- Is that right? - That's right.
我會為油井祈福的
I will bless the well.
在儀式開始前 把我介紹給大家
Before you begin, you should introduce me.
然後我會走到油井那裏...
You'll see me walk up towards the oil well, and...
是油井鑽架
The derrick.
等我走到鑽架那兒之後
You'll see me walk up,
你就可以介紹我的名字了
and then you could say my name.
當你走上來之後...?
When you walk up?
是的 我會走上來 然後你就說...
Yes. You'll see me walk up, and then you could say,
"他是這片大山的愛子..."
"The proud son of these hills...
"照料著主的子民..."
"who tended his Father's flock,"
然後就可以說我的名字了
and then you could say my name.
那好吧
That's fine.
那之後呢?
And what happens then?
之後我們就開始鑽井
Well, then we start the drill.
丹尼爾 雖然祈福儀式很簡單
It's a simple blessing, Daniel,
但非常重要
but an important one.
就幾句話 不會佔用太長時間
It's just a few words. It won't take long.
- 什麼時候開始? - 你什麼時候方便呢 伊萊?
- What time? - What time's good for you, Eli?
- 下午四點 - 那我們就定在四點開始
- 4:00. - Well, let's make it 4:00 then.
- 感謝你來拜訪 - 謝謝您 我走了
- My thanks for your visit. - Good day. Thank you.
各位下午好
Afternoon, everyone.
跟我來
Come with me.
感謝你們每個人來此
I thank you all so much for...
參加這項儀式
visiting with us at this time.
我已有幸拜訪過你們中的某些家庭...
I've had the pleasure of meeting some of you
我也非常希望在今後幾個月裏
and I hope very much in the months to come,
能逐一拜訪每戶人家
I'll be ableto visit with each and every one of you.
比起鑽井找油來
I'm better at digging holes...
我在演說方面的才能要差許多
in the ground than making speeches,
所以就不發表長篇大論了
so let's forget the speech for this evening,
來一段簡單的祈福吧
just make it a simple blessing.
眾所周知 僅憑一個人無法采油
You see, one man doesn't prospect from the ground.
勘探需要發動群體的力量
It takes a whole community of good people,
在場各位就是合適的人選
such as yourselves,
只有這樣才好 大家住在一起
and this is good. We stay together.
一起禱告 一起工作
We pray together, we work together,
倘若有幸 上帝對我們的努力報以微笑...
and if the Good Lord smiles kindly on our endeavor,
我們還能一起分享天賜的財富
we share in the wealth together.
現在 在瑪麗一號油井開鑽之前...
Now, before we spud in Mary's Well Number One,
以這位可愛小姐瑪麗·桑迪之芳名...
named for the lovely Miss Mary Sunday,
她就在我身邊...
here by my side,
她是這片大山的愛女
a proud daughter of these hills,
我想說的是:
I'd just like to say...
願主保佑我們的辛勞
God bless these honest labors of ours,
願他也保佑在場的所有子民
and, of course, God bless you all.
阿門
Amen.
現在去吧
Now go.
馬上就好 請稍候
Won't be a minute.
H.W 給我快點
Fast as you can, H.W.
準備好了沒?
Are you ready to do this?
女士們先生們 我們開始了!
That's it, ladies and gentlemen!
感謝阿爾·羅斯的慷慨
Al Rose has very generously provided...
大家可以享用些茶點...
some refreshments for this occasion
茶點開銷由他負責 謝謝你 阿爾
out of his own pocket. Thank you, Al.
請盡情享用美食
If you'll all just care to help yourselves,
我馬上回來
I'll be back in a minute.
瑪麗
Mary.
瑪麗·桑迪
Mary Sunday.
- 喜歡你的新裙子麼? - 很喜歡 謝謝您
- Do you like your new dress? - Yes. Thank you.
不客氣 我想你會喜歡的
You're welcome. I thought you'd like it.
- 我來這兒你高興麼? - 是的
- Are you happy I came here? - Yes.
你爸爸還打你麼?
Your daddy doesn't hit you anymore, does he?
他現在不打你了吧?
Does he now?
最好他不打了 對麼?
Better not, right?
我會照顧你的
I'll take care of you.
不讓他再打你了 好不好? 不許再打了 現在你可以走了
No more hitting, right? No more hitting. Now go.
去玩吧 不用過來了
Go and play some more and don't come back.
丹尼爾
Daniel?
H.W 沒什麼事 去睡吧
It's okay, H.W. Go back to sleep.
快回去睡覺吧
Go on. Go back to sleep.
丹尼爾
Daniel.
丹尼爾!
Daniel!
怎麼了?
What?
井下死了個人
Lost a man down the well.
- 誰? - 喬伊·岡達
- What man? - Joe Gundha.
- 我認識他麼 - 不
- Did I know him? - No.
發生了什麼事?
What happened?
往上抬
Pick it up.
設好閘
Set the brake.
- 綁好往下放 - 快綁好
- Tie it down. - Tie it on.
該死!
Shit!
我的天哪 屍體在哪兒?
God damn it. Where's the body?
- 正在打撈 - 好
- They're fishing it out now. - All right.
- 鑽頭呢? - 在平台上
- Where's the bit? - It's on the deck.
把屍體弄乾淨 然後給他換套衣服
Clean him up. Put some clothes on him.
然後...
And...
再支一個帳篷
Set up a tent.
任何人下井之前
Anyone goes down into the cellar,
必須告知他人 聽見沒有?
you tell somebody. Yes?
- 聽見了 先生 - 知道了 先生
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
先停工 到中午再說
Shut down till midday.
我還做了一個夢 是的 昨夜 我做了個夢
And I had a vision. Yes, last night, I had a vision
我感覺上帝的氣息貫穿全身
and I felt God's breath move through me.
最後來到我的胃中
And it rolled down into my stomach.
氣息在胃中翻滾
It sloshed around.
我的胃開始說話 不是呼喊 而是低語
And my stomach spoke in a whisper, not a shout,
用手觸摸這名婦人 輕撫她的肌膚
"Touch this woman with your hands and caress her."
親愛的亨特太太...
My dear Mrs. Hunter,
你患有關節炎 是不是?
you have arthritis, don't you?
- 是的 伊萊 - 是啊
- Yes, I do, Eli. - Yes.
有惡魔藏在你的手中 我要把這魔鬼吸出來
The devil is in your hands, and I will suck it out.
這回我不準備用熱焰逼它出來
Now, I will not cast this ghost out with a fever
我內中的氣息
for the new spirit inside me has...
教給我一種新的交流方式
shown me I have a new way to communicate.
用溫柔的低語呼喚
It is a gentle whisper.
出來吧 魔鬼
Get out of here, ghost.
從裏面出來吧
出來
Get out.
出來吧 魔鬼
Get out of here, ghost.
從裏面出來吧
從裏面出來
Get out of here, ghost.
Get out of here.
再也不要停留 永遠離開
Don't you dare turn around and come back.
如果你敢回來
For if you do,
我會將憤怒的力量匯於腳尖 踢碎你的利齒
all the armies of my boot will kick you in the teeth
將你高高拋起 而後摔在泥中
and you will be cast up and thrown in the dirt
墮入地獄 永不超生!
and thrust back to perdition!
只要我有牙齒 就會來撕咬你
And as long as I have teeth, I will bite you,
如果沒有牙齒 就用牙床嚼死你
and if I have no teeth, I will gum you!
只要我有雙拳 就要來痛揍你!
And as long as I have fists, I will bash you!
快點給我離開 魔鬼! 快離開 魔鬼!
Now, get out of here, ghost! Get out of here, ghost!
快離開 魔鬼!
Get out of here, ghost!
它走了!
And it left!
- 哈利路亞! - 哈利路亞!
- Hallelujah! - Hallelujah!
- 讚美主 讚美神聖日! - 讚美主!
- Praise the Lord and his holy days! - Praise God!
阿門! 謝謝各位
Amen! Thank you.
感謝耶穌 感謝主
Thank you, Jesus. Thank you, God.
親愛的亨特太太
My dear Mrs. Hunter.
跟我跳支舞吧
Dance with me.
- 感謝光臨 - 真是一次美妙的布道
- Thanks for coming. - It was a wonderful sermon.
- 明天見? - 明天見
- Will I see you tomorrow? - Yes.
伊萊
Eli.
油井昨晚發生了一場悲劇
Had a tragedy at the well last night.
是的 我聽說了
Yes, I heard.
喬伊·岡達是個有虔誠信仰的人
Joe Gundha was a man of considerable faith.
他的葬禮在明天中午
So if you wish to say a few words,
你可以過來講幾句話
his burial is at noon tomorrow.
丹尼爾 事故本來可以避免
Daniel, this accident could have been avoided.
在未蒙主恩的井下工作...
It is terrible to think of that well
實在是太可怕了
working away out there unblessed.
我的人12小時才換一班
These men work in 12-hour shifts.
他們需要充分的休息
They need their rest.
如果得不到充分休息
If they don't have it,
他們就會犯低級錯誤
they start to make stupid mistakes.
我看見有人在工作時酗酒
I've seen the men drinking.
難道你不應對此採取措施?
Don't you think that has something to do with this?
我的人需要充分休息 油井的生產才有保證
We need these men well-rested to bring in this well.
如果他們總來聽你傳道
They can't get that if they're up...
就無法保證正常的休息
here listening to your gospel,
那樣的話 我們就沒法產油
and then the well can't produce...
大家的錢也成了泡影
and blow gold all over the place.
我希望 當初要能多接觸喬伊就好了
I wish I had more time with Joe Gundha.
也許我能幫他更多
More could have been done.
那樣我們就沒法產油
Then the well can't produce...
大家的錢也成了泡影
and blow gold all over the place.
你能否幫個忙
Now, would you see to it...
將他的私人財產...
that his personal possessions
轉交給他的家人 好麼?
find their way back to his family, please?
謝謝你
Thank you.
聽說你正計劃改建教堂
Heard you were planning some renovations.
是啊 聚會人數越來越多
Yes, our congregation is growing strongly.
我們需要更大的地方
We need more room.
你剛才那場跳神表演真是妙的很啊
That was one goddamn hell of a show.
很榮幸有你相伴 丹尼爾
We were happy to have you, Daniel.
瓦斯 瓦斯!
Gas, gas, gas!
火源滅了! 等在這兒 快滅了火源!
Lights out! Wait here. Wait here. Lights out!
快把那火滅了!
Put that fire out!
他受傷沒有? H.W! 把他遞給我!
Is he hurt? H. W! Hand him down to me!
- 把他放下來! - 接住
- Hand him down! - Here.
- 抓住沒? - 抓住了!
- Got him? - I've got him!
哦 老天
Oh, God.
堅持住
Come on.
把門打開
Open the door.
放開手吧 你沒事了 你安全了
Let go. There you go. You're safe. You're safe.
你現在安全了 我把你帶回來了
You're safe now. I got you here.
你安全了 把手放開吧 小子
You're safe. Let go, son.
告訴我哪兒疼
Tell me where it hurts.
告訴我哪兒疼 告訴我...
Tell me where it hurts. Tell me where...
- 你當時看見沒有? - 沒有
- Did you see this? - No.
告訴我哪兒疼
Tell me where it hurts.
你哪裏受傷了? 你哪裏受傷了?
Where does it hurt you? Where does it hurt you?
- 我聽不見自己的聲音 - 撞到腦袋了?
- I can't hear my voice. - Were you hit in the head?
是不是撞到腦袋了?
Were you hit in the head?
告訴我! 如果是 就告訴我!
Tell me! You have to tell me if you were!
我聽不見自己的聲音
I can't hear my voice.
我得去指揮把火撲滅
I have to go and deal with this now.
在這裏等我
You wait here for me.
明白嗎? 你在這兒等我
You understand? You wait here for me.
我就回來 我馬上回來
I'll be back. I'll be back in a minute.
- 你等著 - 你別走!
- Wait here. - Don't leave!
我會照顧你的
I'm going to take care of you. Wait.
呆著別動 我來搞定
Stay here, son. I'm going to fix this.
- 請你別走! - 你會沒事的
- Don't leave! - You're going to be fine!
在這兒等我
Wait for me here!
- 把他按住 按住他 - 不要走!
- Hold him down. Hold him down. - Don't leave!
得把繩纜割斷 丹尼爾!
Got to break the cables, Daniel!
給我一把錘子!
Get me a hammer!
給你
Here you go.
後退!
Get back!
- 邁克爾 - 先生?
- Michael! - Sir!
帶上戴夫 再叫兩個人 去拿水管
Take Dave and two of the fellas, pick up some hoses.
比利 快去保護頂棚
Billy, protect the roof.
溫度太高就不好辦了
Don't wait before it gets too hot.
幹嘛那樣愁眉不展?
What are you looking so miserable about?
我們腳下是油的海洋!
There's a whole ocean of oil under our feet!
它們只屬於我 沒有第二個主人!
No one can get at it except for me.
H.W還好麼?
H.W. Okay?
不好
No, he isn't.
- 他在哪兒? - 在食堂
- Where is he? - Mess room.
別哼哼了 夠了 H.W. 別哼哼了
That's enough now. That's enough,H.W. That's enough.
聽見我說話麼? 能聽見麼?
Do you hear me? Can you hear me in there?
夠了
That's enough.
- 抓住他的腳 - 抓住腳了
- Grab his legs. - I have his legs.
- 不 不 - 別這樣 小伙子
- No. Nope. - No, lad.
把那個給我
Give me that.
穩住 就這樣
Steady. That's it.
- 放鬆點孩子 放鬆 - 一會兒就好了
- Easy, boy. Easy. - Soon be over.
好 就這樣
Yeah, and that's good.
現在換另一邊 把他翻過來
Now the other side. Turn him over.
馬上就好
Almost done.
好了
That's it.
過來 結束了 都結束了
Come here. It's over. It's over.
我們在舊金山認識什麼人麼?
Who do we know in San Francisco
或者洛杉磯 有誰可以幫忙的?
or Los Angeles, who could work with...
我們可以找個人 來當H.W的老師
You know, we could... Someone, a teacher for H.W.
你來處理此事如何?
How could you figure out that?
打電話給...該死 那人叫什麼來著?
Now, call... God damn it, what's his name?
舊金山的鮑勃·布羅迪?
Bob Brody in San Francisco?
打電話給鮑勃·布羅迪 讓他找個老師過來
Call Bob Brody and get someone down here.
我馬上去辦
I'll do it right away.
我們什麼時候能拿到錢 丹尼爾?
When do we get our money, Daniel?
你不是天命神醫麼?
Aren't you a healer?
你不是聖靈附體麼?
And a vessel for the Holy Spirit?
什麼時候來把我兒子的耳朵治好?
When are you coming over and make my son hear again?
會不會啊你?
Can't you do that?
如果讓我為油井祈福
If you had let me bless the well,
這種事根本不會發生
this wouldn't have happened.
- 丹尼爾... - 你不該說這種話
- Daniel. - You shouldn't have done that.
你還欠第三啟示教會五千美金...
You owe the Church of the Third Revelation $5,000
我們當初約定好的!
as part of the arrangement that we made!
小矮人 想得美 門都沒有!
Don't even try it, you little runt!
讓你嘗嘗泥漿浴的味道吧...
You splash around in here.
這樣才對 這樣好多了...
That's it, that's it.
我會把你就地活埋 伊萊
I'm going to bury you underground, Eli.
把你活埋了!
I'm going to bury you underground.
你太蠢了 埃布爾
You are a stupid man, Abel.
是你把生人請了進來
You've let someone come in here...
讓他在我們頭上撒野
and walk all over us.
是你讓他進來 讓他在此胡作非為
You let him in and do his work here,
你太蠢了 破壞了原先美好的一切
and you are a stupid man for what we could have had.
是上帝讓我這麼做的 伊萊 我已經盡力了
I followed His word, Eli. I tried.
你一直乾坐著 根本沒出力
You didn't do anything but sit down.
你不僅懶惰 而且愚蠢
You're lazy, and you're stupid.
你想用愚蠢來...
Do you think God is going to...
換取上帝的救贖?
save you for being stupid?
主不會救贖愚蠢的靈魂 埃布爾
He doesn't save stupid people, Abel.
就你做的這點破事 真想把你捏死
I will tear you apart for what you've done,
你這個大蠢蛋!
you stupid man!
他怎麼來的? 你知不知道? 我知道!
How did he come here? Do you really know? I know!
- 兒子 你別...不要... - 不許吵!
- Son, don't do this, please! - Be quiet!
閉上你的嘴 埃布爾! 是你那個蠢兒子干的
Shut your mouth, Abel! It was your stupid son!
是保羅讓那傢伙過來的 我知道
It was Paul who told him to come here. I know it.
他跟那傢伙說
He went to him and he said,
"我那愚蠢軟弱的爸爸會讓出土地的..."
"My stupid, weak father will give away his lots.
"快去搞定他吧"...你果然就被人家輕鬆搞定了
"Go and take him." And you let it happen.
真是有其父必有其子呀
A stupid father to a stupid son.
出來吧
Get out of there!
有什麼事麼?
Can I help you?
丹尼爾?
Daniel?
- 你是哪位? - 我叫亨利
- Who's that? - My name is Henry.
什麼?
Yeah?
我叫亨利
I'm Henry.
能為您做什麼?
What can I do for you?
我是亨利·普萊維 來自豐迪拉克郡
I'm Henry Plainview. I'm from Fond du Lac.
我是你的兄弟 我們同父異母
I'm your brother, from another mother.
我父親是歐內斯特
Ernest is my father.
你是誰?
Who are you?
亨利
Henry.
瑪麗·布蘭茲是你的母親?
Mary Branch? Is that your mother?
是的 先生 正是
Yes, sir, that's right.
從報上聽說了你的油井
I read about your gusher in the paper,
還有你的成就
about your success.
聽說我發家了 你就來找我了?
You heard about my strike? You just show up?
我們的父親過世了
Our father's dead.
我聽說歐內斯特死了 就想來找你
Ernest died, I heard. I wanted to find you.
什麼時候死的?
When?
三個月前 安娜貝爾寄給我一封信
Three months ago. I got a letter from Annabelle.
我的姐姐安娜貝爾?
My sister, Annabelle?
- 她現在在哪兒? - 還在老家 豐迪拉克郡
- Where is she? - Still at home. Fond du Lac.
你大老遠從威斯康辛過來 就為了告訴我這個?
You came all the way from Wisconsin to tell me this?
我從新墨西哥州過來的 我在那兒待了一段時間
I'm coming from New Mexico. I've been there.
就為了過來找你
I came to find you.
你知道有我這個兄弟麼?
Did you know about me?
你有證件麼?
Do you have identification?
那封信你帶了沒?
Do you have this letter?
- 你從哪兒來? - 新墨西哥州
- Where are you coming from? - From New Mexico.
我知道 在哪個城市呢?
Yes, I know, but from where?
在銀城 我在那兒待了兩年
Silver City. I've been there for two years.
多年來我一直想成立自己的鑽探隊
I was trying drilling of my own for years.
在德克薩斯和路易斯安那租地探油
Getting leases in Texas. Louisiana.
找到油了麼?
Anything that produced?
沒有 比起你的成功 我毫無所獲
No. Not like your success, no.
- 結婚了麼? - 沒有
- Are you married? - No.
我曾坐過大牢
I spent time in jail.
那日子真難熬
I had a stretch of very bad time.
身無分文 在路易斯安那被人抓了
I had nothing. I was picked up in Louisiana.
身上拴著鐵鏈
I worked on a chain gang...
做了半年修路苦力
for six months building roads.
真是不堪回首啊
That was a very hard time.
你結婚了沒有?
Are you married?
你為了什麼坐牢的?
What were you in jail for?
說真的
Believe it or not,
雖然我也幹過不少壞事
for all the terrible things I've gotten myself into,
但那次被抓的時候 我什麼壞事也沒幹
when they picked me up, I hadn't done anything.
但我也是罪有應得...
But I've done my share of things
具體的罪惡麼 恕我不能明述了
that shouldn't be talked about.
喝了它...喝了它!
Drink it. Drink it!
來吧
Come on.
那麼...
So...
你想要什麼 亨利?
What do you want, Henry?
什麼也不要
Nothing.
如果不嫌棄
If you can spare something,
我願意為你打工
I can work for you in any way.
不久後我可能還得繼續漂泊
I know I'll keep moving, before long,
最後回老家豐迪拉克
to get back to Fond du Lac.
- 你有積蓄麼? - 有一點
- Do you have any money? - Some.
- 但不多 - 跟我說實話
- Not much. - Just answer me directly.
你剛才還說"什麼也不要"
You say "nothing",
然後又說想留下幹活
then you say you'd like to stay and work.
如果你只說想留下幹活
And it's better, I'd just like to...
我聽了會更舒服
hear you say you'd like to be here.
我想留下
I'd like to be here.
我幹活很賣力的
I'm a good worker.
我在鑽油平台上幹過 也修過鐵路
I worked cable tool rigs, built railroads.
不需要你多加關照的
I won't need any favors.
好
Good.
我媽媽知道這事麼?
What did my mother know?
我不知道
I don't know.
也許她知道 但故意迴避此事
I don't know if she knew and looked the other way,
裝作不知 是否如此我不清楚
if she never knew.
你為何離開家?
Why did you leave?
我只知道你和父親不合
I know you didn't get on with our father.
我曾為地質勘探隊工作過 並隨他們一起去了堪薩斯...
I worked for Geological Survey and went to Kansas.
我沒法留在家裏 覺得沒法呆
I couldn't stay there. I just couldn't.
我不喜歡給自己找理由
I don't like to explain myself.
- 亨利 你容易動怒嗎? - 為了什麼?
- Are you an angry man, Henry? - About what?
那你會嫉妒嗎? 容易心生嫉妒嗎?
Are you envious? Do you get envious?
我想沒有...沒有吧
I don't think so, no.
我的內心總在鬥爭
I have a competition in me.
我不願意見到其他人成功
I want no one else to succeed.
- 對大部分人 我都懷有恨意 - 我心中已經沒有那些東西了
- I hate most people. - That part of me is gone.
投入工作的熱情 遭受挫折的懊惱
Working and not succeeding,
那些失敗的往昔都已離我遠去...
all my failures have left me...
我已經不在乎了
I just don't care.
在我心裏的東西 在你心裏也應該有
Well, if it's in me, it's in you.
有很多次 我看著別人
There are times when I look at people...
找不到半點中意的地方
and I see nothing worth liking.
我想掙足夠多的鈔票
I want to earn enough money I can...
多到足以遠離俗世的煩擾
get away from everyone.
你兒子怎麼辦?
What will you do about your boy?
我不知道
I don't know.
事情會發生變化也說不定
Maybe it'll change.
昨日是否會重回你身邊? 我不知道
Does your sound come back to you? I don't know.
也許沒有人知道
Maybe no one knows that.
- 連醫生也不知道 - 孩子他媽呢?
- Doctor might not know that. - Where's his mother?
我不想談論這事...
I don't want to talk about those things.
我能看到人性最醜陋的那一面
I see the worst in people, Henry.
負面印象太多
I don't need to look past...
甚至無需刻意回想
seeing them to get all I need.
經過長年日積月累
I've built up my hatreds over the years,
我的恨意越蓄越深
little by little.
你來之後 在我的生活中 又打開了一扇嶄新的窗
Having you here gives me a second breath of life.
我不能再獨自一個人戰鬥了
I can't keep doing this on my own
和這些人...抗爭
with these people.
丹尼爾 丹尼爾 快醒醒! 丹尼爾!
Daniel! Daniel, wake up! Daniel!
我得去和列車長說幾句話
Just have to go and have a word with the conductor.
很快就回來
I'll be right back.
你呆著...懂了麼? 待在這兒別動
You stay here. You understand? You stay here.
我馬上回來
I'll be right back.
不! 不!
No! No!
不!!
No!
- 特爾福德! - 普萊維
- Tilford! - Plainview.
我兄弟亨利·普萊維 來自豐迪拉克
This is my brother Henry Plainview from Fond du Lac.
H.M. 特爾福德 很高興認識你
H.M. Tilford. Pleasure.
- 亨利·普萊維 - J.J.卡特
- Henry Plainview. - J.J. Carter.
那麼...
So...
- 我們開始? - 好吧
- Shall we? - Yes.
你兒子情況如何?
How's your boy?
謝謝關心
Thank you for asking.
有什麼要我們幫忙麼?
Is there anything we can do?
有你的關心就足夠了
Thanks for asking is enough.
那麼 你打算怎麼辦?
So what are your plans?
你是在問我這裏的地怎麼賣?
Is this about buying up my tracts here?
是的
Yes.
電報裏提的是我在野狼山的租約
The cable was about my Coyote Hills lease.
那份租約我們也想買
We'd like that, too.
野狼山那份 你們開價多少?
What's your offer on Coyote Hills?
十五萬美金 轉讓所有權利
We'll offer 150,000 for full title.
沒問題...接下來呢?
That's a deal. What's next?
你在小波士頓有11000英畝地
You have 11,000 acres in Little Boston.
有一口出油井...
You have one proven well
- 但已受損... - 有三口出油井
- that was damaged... - I have three wells proven.
看來你們調查不夠
You haven't been paying attention.
出油井一共三口
That's three proven wells.
你現在只需坐等收錢
We'll make you a millionaire while you're sitting
我們可以讓你馬上變成百萬富翁
here from one minute to the next.
賣了地之後我還能幹嘛?
And what else would I do with myself?
你在問我?
Are you asking me?
我以後還能幹嘛?
What else would I do with myself?
照顧你兒子
Take care of your son.
我又不瞭解你想幹嘛
I don't know what you would do.
如果此刻你是我 標準石油的人想來買你的地...
If you were me and Standard offered to buy what
還出價一百萬美金 就會想問原因 為什麼你們要這麼做?
you had for a million dollars, why? So, why?
你知道原因
You know why.
我建議你們學學其他人
Yeah, you fellas should just...
憑自己的力量去挖去找
scratch around in the dirt
而不是直接用錢...
and find it like the rest of us,
去換別人辛勤的果實
instead of buying up someone else's hard work.
年輕人 我自己也挖過找過
I've scratched around the dirt, son.
你們是不是準備上調運價啊?
You going to change your shipping costs?
我們才不會操縱運價呢
We don't dictate shipping costs.
這都是鐵路公司的決定...
That's railroad business.
鐵路公司不是你們的產業?
You don't own the railroads?
你們當然會啦 這點毫無疑問
'Course you do. Of course you do.
你準備把這些油送到哪兒去?
Where you going to put it all?
到哪兒?
Where?
如果想造一條管線
Build a pipeline?
然後和聯合石油做買賣 那就請便...
Make a deal with Union Oil? Be my guest.
但如果你的計劃沒能實現...
But if you can't pull it off,
到時候守著偌大一片油田
you've got an ocean of oil...
卻無處可去 豈不是很慘
under your feet with nowhere to go.
為什麼不交給我們? 我們會讓你發大財
Why not turn it over to us? We'll make you rich.
你可以騰出時間來照顧孩子
You spend time with your boy.
這兒的油田是一個驚人的發現
It's a great discovery.
現在讓我們來協助你吧
Now, let us help you.
你竟然教訓我該怎麼帶孩子...
Did you just tell me how to run my family?
你的地現在能賣個好價錢 這一點也許更為重要
It might be more important now that you've proven
我們也願出大錢買下你的地
the field and we're offering to buy you out.
總有一天晚上我會去找你
One night I'm going to come to you,
進你的屋子
inside of your house,
或是趁你熟睡的時候
or wherever you're sleeping,
用刀把你的喉嚨割斷
and I'm going to cut your throat.
什麼?
What?
你在說些什麼啊? 你是不是瘋了?
What are you talking about? Have you gone crazy?
- 你沒聽明白我說的? - 我全聽見了
- Did you hear what I said? - I heard what you said,
你要幹嘛?
why did you say it?
不許教訓我該怎樣撫養兒子
You don't tell me about my son.
你發什麼瘋?
Why are you acting insane...
竟然威脅要割我喉嚨
and threatening to cut my throat?
不許教訓我該怎樣撫養兒子
You don't tell me about my son.
我根本沒教訓你!
I'm not telling you anything!
請你理智一點
I'm asking you to be reasonable.
如果剛才我有所冒犯 我道歉
If I've offended you, I apologize.
那你就等著瞧好吧
You'll see what I can do.
這三千英畝是...
This parcel here is the 3,000-acre...
是B.L.哈珀的農場
ranch owned by B.L. Harper.
這是聖路易歐比斯珀郡的郡屬土地
This is San Luis Obispo County land.
還有從這兒直到海岸 都被聯合石油收購了
And from here to the coast, it's all Union Oil.
這兒呢? 為什麼我沒買下這裏?
What's this? Why don't I own this?
- 為什麼我沒買? - 這是班迪的地產
- Why don't I own this? - That's the Bandy tract.
就是那個在我們收購土地的時候 拒不合作的老頭
He was the holdout, when we were doing the buying.
他想先和你談談
He had hoped to speak with you.
你的管線不能繞過他的地盤麼?
Can't you just build the pipeline around this tract?
我要有這個能耐 就能把蒂哈查皮山再加長50英里了
Can I build around 50 miles of Tehachapi mountains?
別在我面前說蠢話 阿爾
Don't be thick in front of me, Al.
我可以再去問他
I can go to him again.
不用 我親自去和他說
No, I'll go and talk to the man.
我去說 你們學著點
I'll talk to him. Show you how it's done.
就到這兒 亨利 你收拾一下
All right. Pack it up, Henry.
我兒子的房間多大?
How big is his room?
他和另一個孩子合住
He's sharing with another boy.
- 和誰? - 一個比他大的孩子 12歲左右
- Who? - An older boy. About 12.
名叫巴拉德 在那兒已經住了一年
He's been there for a year. Named Ballard.
他的房間有多大?
How big is the room?
不大不小 夠兩個人住的
It's a fair size. Got enough space.
你要帶亨利去見聯合石油的人?
Are you taking Henry with you to meet Union Oil?
- 你是威廉·班迪的兒子? - 他的孫子
- Are you the son of William Bandy? - Grandson.
- 他在麼? - 不 他出去了
- Is he here? - No, he's out.
他去哪兒了?
Where is he?
都說了他出去了 你有什麼事?
Told you, he's out. Now, what do you want?
我是丹尼爾·普萊維
I'm Daniel Plainview.
想和你爺爺談談他地產的事情
I want to talk with him about his property.
要談些什麼?
About what?
我還是和他親自談比較好
I believe I'll talk with him about that.
- 你是個油礦主 對不對? - 是的
- You're that oilman, aren't you? - That's right.
我們不要你來挖油
We don't want you drilling out here.
我也不想來啊...他什麼時候回來?
I don't want it either. Now, when will he be back?
幾天以後吧
Few days.
跟他說 我想找他談談
Tell him I'd like to speak with him.
是挖油的事
Not about drilling.
我一周後再來
And I'll be back in a week.
把這根留在玻璃陳列櫃裏
Put that in a glass case.
這杯酒敬給聯合石油...
Here's to Union Oil.
還有數百英里的輸油管線...
Hundred miles of pipeline,
以及本州所有的...
and all the independent producers...
獨立油礦主
of this great state.
乾杯
Cheers.
在豐迪拉克老家有幢房子
There's that house in Fond du Lac
是約翰·霍利斯特造的 你記得那房子麼?
that John Hollister built. Do you remember it?
小時候我覺得
I thought as a boy...
那是我所見過的最漂亮的房子
that was the most beautiful house I'd ever seen,
夢想能擁有她
and I wanted it.
我想住在那房子裏
I wanted to live in it.
在裏面吃飯...
And eat in it.
在裏面打掃
And clean it.
打小我就想生很多孩子
And even as a boy, I wanted to have children
讓他們在房外奔跑戲耍
to run around in it.
現在的你能把任何夢想變成現實
You can have anything you'd like now, Daniel.
你應該去實現自己的夢想
And you should.
你準備在哪兒建房子?
Where are you going to build it?
也許就建在這兒 在海邊
Here, maybe. Near the ocean.
按照那幢房子的樣式建?
Would you make it look like that house?
現在如果再見到那幢房子 我也許會嗤之以鼻的
I think if I saw that house now, it'd make me sick.
我們去大吃一頓吧 再找些女人樂樂
We can eat and get some women.
就帶她們去桃樹舞廳...
Take them to the Peachtree dance.
我說 先把自己灌個半醉
I say get liquored up...
再帶女人去桃樹舞廳如何
and take them to the Peachtree dance.
好啊
Yeah.
拜託 給我點錢吧
Can I have some money, please?
給我點錢好嗎?
我想問你幾件事
I want you to tell me something.
問什麼?
What?
希爾家旁邊的農場叫什麼名字?
What's the name of the farm next to the Hill House?
希爾家旁邊的農場
What was the name of the farm...
叫什麼名字?
next to the Hill House?
- 我記不起來了... - 你是誰?
- I can't remember... - Who are you?
我會走的 丹尼爾
I'll leave, Daniel.
你到底是誰?
Who are you?
我誰都不是
I'm no one.
讓我起身吧 我馬上消失
Just let me get up and go.
我有兄弟麼?
Do I have a brother?
我在國王城遇見一個人
I met a man in King City...
他說他是你的兄弟
who said he was your brother.
我們做了幾個月的朋友
We were friends for months.
在國王城一起共事
Working in King City.
他想來這兒找你 丹尼爾
And he wanted to make his way to you, Daniel.
但當時我們沒有錢
We didn't have any money.
後來他得肺結核死了
He died of tuberculosis.
不是死於暴力...
He wasn't harmed.
也不是被殺的 就是正常的那種死亡
Wasn't killed, nothing bad.
但他跟我提起過你
But he told me about you,
於是我借用了他的身份
and I just took his story,
拿了他的日記
used his diary.
丹尼爾
Daniel.
丹尼爾 我是你的朋友
Daniel, I'm your friend.
我不想傷害你
I'm not trying to hurt you.
從來沒想過...
Never.
只想找口飯吃
Just survive.
不!
No!
哪位?
Who is it?
我叫班迪
I'm Bandy.
是你 你是...
Yes. Yes.
威廉·班迪
William Bandy.
我想租你的地
Yeah, I'd like to lease your land.
我曾邀請你去我那兒談...
I had asked for you to come and talk to me before.
可你在忙著租地 沒來找我
When you were leasing land.
說的沒錯
That's right, yes.
你知道 我兒子病得厲害 我抽不開身
My boy's been very sick, you know.
那是在你兒子生病之前的事
This was before your boy got sick.
我聽說你想修一條管線
Now, I know that you would like to build a pipeline
而且要經過我的土地
through my property.
我聽得沒錯吧?
Is that right, what I've heard?
完全正確
It's absolutely right. And,
那好...
well...
只是一根八英吋粗的管子
Eight inch pipe.
如果你點頭 我們可以把它埋在地下...
It could be buried with your consent.
我保證 絕不會給您帶來任何影響
I guarantee you absolutely no disruption...
上帝...
God.
上帝把你要做的事告訴了我
God has told me what you must do.
我要做的事?
And what is that?
你得在耶穌基督的聖血中受洗
You should be washed in the blood of Jesus Christ.
但我已經做了
But I am.
我已經受洗了 班迪先生 我早就受洗了
I have been washed, Mr. Bandy. I have been.
這是你唯一的救贖之道
It's your only way to salvation.
是你得償所願的唯一方法
And your only way for what you want.
你可以來...
You can take it at the Church...
第三啟示教堂
of the Third Revelation.
我可以付你三千美元
I'll pay you $3,000.
我希望你加入我們的教會
I'd like you to be part of our church.
我付你五千美元
I'll pay you $5,000.
快來受洗吧
Be baptized.
請求主寬恕你的罪
Be forgiven for the sin that you've done.
你說的罪惡...是指什麼 班迪先生?
What sin are you referring to, Mr. Bandy?
因為我在這裏鑽井?
My sin of drilling?
我真心希望每個人都能得到救贖 大家說是不是?
I truly wish everyone could be saved, don't you?
是的
Yes.
只可惜事實並非如我們所願
I am afraid that's just not the case.
號稱所有人都能得救
The doctrine of universal salvation...
那是謊言 大家說是不是?
is a lie, is it not?
- 是騙人的 - 是騙人的
- It's a lie. - It's a lie.
我希望每個人都能得救
I wish everyone could be saved,
但這不可能! 不可能人人都得救!
but they won't. No, they won't.
要想得救 你只有...
You will never be saved if you...
接受聖血的洗禮!
Reject the blood.
好
Good.
這兒有尋求救贖的罪人麼?
Now, is there a sinner here looking for salvation?
我指新來的人
A new member?
我再問一遍：
I'll ask it again.
這兒有尋求主赦的罪人麼?
Is there a sinner here looking for God?
有
Yes.
讓我來
Allow me.
謝謝你的光臨 丹尼爾兄弟
Thank you for coming, brother Daniel.
謝謝你 伊萊
Thank you, Eli.
我們這兒有位...
We have a sinner with us here...
希望得到救贖的罪人
who wishes for salvation!
- 丹尼爾 你是罪人麼 - 是的
- Daniel, are you a sinner? - Yes.
主聽不見你的話 丹尼爾
The Lord can't hear you, Daniel.
大聲說給主聽 說響點
Say it to him. Go ahead and speak to him.
沒關係的
It's all right.
- 好的 - 跪對上帝
- Yes. - Down on your knees.
向他祈禱
Pray to him.
抬頭向上蒼 說出你的罪過
Look up to the sky and say it.
你想讓我說什麼?
What do you want me to say?
丹尼爾 你來到這裏
Daniel, you've come here...
並且帶來了利益和財富
and you've brought good and wealth,
但也帶來了惡習
but you have also brought your bad habits...
你是個墮落者
as a backslider.
你追逐著身邊的美色
You've lusted after women,
卻捨棄了自己的孩子
and you have abandoned your child.
你捨棄了親手養大的孩子
Your child, that you raised, you have abandoned
只因為他有病 因為你有罪
all because he was sick and you have sinned.
現在跟我說:" 我是一個罪人"
So say it now. I am a sinner.
- 我是一個罪人 - 大聲說
- I am a sinner. - Say it louder.
- 我是一個罪人 - 我是一個罪人
- I am a sinner. - I am a sinner.
再大聲點 丹尼爾! 我是一個罪人!
Louder, Daniel! I am a sinner!
- 我是一個罪人! - 主啊 我錯了!
- I am a sinner. - I am sorry, Lord.
- 主啊 我錯了! - 請賜我聖血吧!
- I am sorry, Lord. - I want the blood.
- 請賜我聖血吧! - 你捨棄了自己的孩子
- I want the blood. - You have abandoned your child.
我捨棄了自己的孩子
I have abandoned my child.
- 我絕不再甘墮落 - 我絕不再甘墮落
- I will never backslide. - I will never backslide.
我曾迷失 現又重歸本我
I was lost, but now I am found.
I was lost, but now I'm found.
我捨棄了自己的孩子
I have abandoned my child.
跟我說 快說
Say it. Say it.
我捨棄了自己的孩子
I abandoned my child.
大聲點 說大聲點!
Say it louder. Say it louder!
我捨棄了自己的孩子!
I've abandoned my child!
我丟下自己的親兒子不管!
I've abandoned my boy!
乞求聖血吧
Now beg for the blood!
快給我聖血 伊萊 讓我離開這兒
Just give me the blood, Eli. Let me get out of here.
主啊 請賜我聖血 驅走我體內的惡魔!
Give me the blood, Lord, and let me get away!
你是否願接受耶穌基督做你的主 認他做你的救贖者?
Do you accept Jesus Christ as your Lord and Savior?
- 是的 我願意 - 快出來吧 惡魔!
- Yes, I do. - Get out of here, devil!
出來吧 惡魔! 出來吧 罪惡!
Out, devil! Out, sin!
讓我感受主的力量吧 伊萊
Let me feel the power of the Lord, Eli.
你是否願接受...
Do you accept
第三啟示教會成為...
the Church of the Third Revelation...
你靈魂的引路人?
as your spiritual guide?
快給我出來!
Get out of here, ghost!
你的主在哪兒 伊萊?
Where is your Lord, Eli?
給我出來 滾回你的老窩去!
Get out! Go back where you belong!
他在哪兒? 他在那兒!
Where is he? There he is!
你願接受耶穌基督為救世主麼?
Do you accept Jesus Christ as your Savior?
我願意
Yes, I do.
"你肩上的罪是否卸空
Would you be free from the burden of sin?
"神力蘊於聖血中
There's power in the blood
Power in the blood
"你是否擊敗過惡魔 贏得光榮
Would you o'er evil a victory win?
管線到手了
There's a pipeline.
"血中的神力無比尊崇
There's wonderful power in the blood
"神力啊 神力 偉大的神力
There is power, power wonder-working power
存於耶穌寶血之中..."
In the blood of the Lamb
讚美主!
Praise the Lord!
歡迎入教 普萊維兄弟
Welcome to the fold, brother Plainview.
歡迎你 普萊維兄弟 願主保佑你
Welcome, brother Daniel. God bless you.
願主保佑你
God bless you.
- 哈利路亞 - 阿門
- Hallelujah. - Amen.
歡迎回家 兄弟
Welcome home, brother.
好了...到此為止吧
That's enough. That's enough, now.
他得自己將聖靈引入體內
He must take the spirit in on his own.
我們又多了一位新的兄弟
We have a new member.
- 是的 兄弟 - 哈利路亞
- Yes, brother. - Hallelujah.
- 哈利路亞 - 阿門
- Hallelujah. - Amen.
- 普萊維先生非常慷慨 - 親愛的瑪麗...
- My sweet Mary. - Mr. Plainview has been generous
他願捐出五千美金
enough to make a $5,000 donation
捐給教會 雖然這筆錢還沒到帳
to the church which we are still waiting for.
這感覺真好 這感覺真好
That does me good. That does me good.
歡迎回家 兒子
Welcome home, son.
這位是喬治·雷諾茲
This here's George Reynolds.
聾校的老師
Teacher from the deaf school.
- 普萊維先生 - 弗萊徹
- Mr. Plainview. - Fletcher.
你都變得這麼重了
You're too heavy for me.
想吃點東西麼?
Do you want to get something to eat?
看見沒 那邊就是輸油管線 一直通到大海
That's the pipeline, see? All the way to the sea.
過來
Come here.
我愛你 兒子
I love you, son.
讓我好好看看你
Let's take a look at you.
好了 夠了 夠了...
All right. That's it, that's it. That's it.
讓我們弄點好吃的吧
Let's get some decent food inside of you.
我們到這兒來
That's all we need here...
就是來吃一頓豐盛高檔的大餐
is a good, strong, expensive meal.
你餓了麼?
You hungry?
- 服務生? - 您好 先生
- Waiter? - Yes, sir.
兩份牛排 一杯威士忌 給這位年輕人來一杯水
Two steaks, a whiskey, and water for him.
- 再來一杯羊奶 - 好的 先生
- And goat's milk. - Very good, sir.
我們請了位老師來幫你
We're going to have this teacher help you.
他會照顧好我們大家的
He's going to help take care of all of this.
聽明白了?
Understand?
我需要你 需要你的幫助
'Cause I need you. Need your help.
現在我們的公司已一切就緒
Got everything we need now to build this company.
過來...
Come here.
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 你好麼? - 很高興再次見到你
- How are you doing? - It's nice to see you again.
- 我們需要四個人的桌子 - 我馬上派人安排
- We need four. - I'll have them right up.
- 下午好 丹尼爾 - 哦 特爾福德
- Good afternoon, Daniel. - Tilford.
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 你好 我是H.M.特爾福德! - 用不著那麼大聲
- Hello! H.M. Tilford! - You don't have to shout.
很高興見到你們
Pleasure.
小波士頓這兒不錯
It's good to be in Little B.
- 這裏應該下點雨 - 是啊 沒錯
- Could use some rain out here. - Yeah, we could.
- 我們的飲料來了 - R.J. 倫敦烤肉味道如何?
- There we go. - R.J., how's the London broil?
我們比這些人先要的飲料
Believe we ordered these drinks before those people.
R.J. 說說看 這兒的烤肉如何?
R.J., tell us. How's the London broil?
對不起 先生們 我很抱歉
Excuse me, gentlemen. Sorry.
先生 我很抱歉
I am sorry about that, sir.
你們的牛排馬上就來
I'll have your steaks right out.
- 聽說海龜湯很不錯 - 是麼?
- So that green turtle soup is fantastic. - Is it?
非常美味
It's delicious.
聽上去合我胃口
Sounds good to me.
標準石油願出一百萬美元
So Standard offered us a million dollars...
收購我在小波士頓的租地
for the Little Boston leases.
我告訴特爾福德 讓他一邊去
I told H.M. Tilford where he could shove that.
於是我找了聯合石油做生意! 還修了一條管線!
And we made a deal with Union! On the pipeline!
把腳下的這片油海慢慢運出去
And that whole ocean of oil underneath our fields.
- 15萬美金 - 好
...$150,000. - Yes.
我們需要錢開井
We needed the money to drill.
- 那人是誰? - 我去和他說
- Who is this guy? - I go out to meet him.
他的地裏有油
He's getting oil on the property.
我們想買下所有權
We're trying to make a claim on it.
然後給他一百萬報價
Offered him a million dollars.
- 他卻一口回絕 - 好了 我餓了
- Turned us down flat. - Well, I'm hungry.
桔子餡餅 土豆泥 還有青豆...
Orange fritters, mashed potatoes, green peas.
- 都是這種東西? - 好罷
- All the way around? - All right.
等一等
Hold on.
請你往那邊看
I want you to look over there.
丹尼爾 我來介紹一下...
Daniel, let me introduce...
往那邊看 看見沒?
Look over there. You see?
那是我兒子 你看見他了麼?
That's my son. See him?
- 我看見了 - 你看見了?
- Yes. - Do you see?
我看見他了
I see him.
別教訓我該怎麼撫養後代
You don't tell me how to raise my family.
我警告你 別教訓我該怎麼撫養後代
I told you not to tell me how to raise my family.
丹尼爾...
Daniel...
你現在看見什麼了?
So what do you see?
我很高興你的生意能...
I'm very happy for you that the deal...
是的 我和聯合石油的生意成了
Yes, I made a deal with Union.
- 我的兒子也很快樂 很安全 - 恭喜你
- My son is happy. He's safe. - Congratulations.
- 現在由我照顧他 所以... - 那樣很好
- I'm taking care of him now, so... - Excellent.
你看上去就像個傻瓜 是不是啊 特爾福德?
You look like a fool, don't you, Tilford?
- 是的 - 是的
- Yes. - Yes.
說"是"就對了
Yes, you do.
請見諒 先生們
Excuse me, gentlemen.
請原諒我 先生們 也請原諒他
Excuse me, gentlemen. Excuse him, gentlemen.
我早告訴你我會這麼做了
I told you what I was going to do.
我的兒子...
My son.
桑迪先生
Mr. Sunday,
聽說你要離開我們教區
I understand that you're leaving our fair community.
- 是的 我打算出去傳道 - 你要去哪兒?
- Yes, I'm going on a mission. - Where you going?
去石油谷和塔夫脫 然後到貝克斯菲爾德
Oildale, Taft, and then on to Bakersfield.
那麼 我想說...
Well, I want you to know...
三刻鐘時間
Three quarters of an hour.
你為我們做了很多
...you done a great job for us.
謝謝 我在祈禱時會祝福你的
Thank you. You will be in my prayers.
非常感謝你
I thank you very much.
聯合石油公司 加州聖保拉市
Union Oil Company, Santa Paula, California.
"婦人說 先生 請把這水賜給我"
"The woman saith unto him, 'Sir, give me this water
"叫我不渴"
"'and I shall thirst not,
"也不用來這麼遠打水"
"'neither come hither to draw."'
進來 進來吧
Come in, come in.
我們能單獨談談麼?
Can we be alone?
這是我最親密的夥伴 我對他沒有秘密
This is my closest associate. He hears everything.
我還是想和你私下交談
I'd prefer to speak to you in private.
你又張不了嘴
You can't speak.
那就用你的手比劃吧
So why don't you flap your hands about
讓那誰誰代你說 這些日子你都去哪兒了
and have what's-his-name tell me where you've been.
你以為我不知道你小子去了哪兒?
Or do you think I don't know?
關於此事我很難開口...
This is hard for me to say.
先要說的是 我非常非常愛你
I'll tell you first, I love you very much.
從你身上 我學會了熱愛事業
I've learned to love what I do because of you.
我準備離開這裏
I'm leaving here.
我要去墨西哥
I'm going to Mexico.
我還會帶上瑪麗 去墨西哥
I'm taking Mary, and I'm going to Mexico.
我很想念在外工作的生活
I miss working outside.
也很想念油田
I miss the fields.
可能過不多久
It'll only be for a time,
我會成立自己的鑽探隊
for me to do my own drilling
然後開創自己的公司
and start my own company.
是時候改變一下了
It's time to make a change.
這樣一來 你我就變成對手了
This makes you my competitor.
不不 我沒有那個意思...
No. No, it's not like that.
你就是這個意思 孩子
It is like that, boy.
你自己的公司? 不錯嘛!
Your own company, huh?
是的
That's right.
在墨西哥?
In Mexico?
是的
Yes.
犯什麼渾啊你!
You are making such a misstep.
到底想幹嘛?
So, what are you doing?
我知道我們有很多事意見不一致
I know you and I have disagreed over many things.
我寧願當你是父親 而不是合作夥伴
I'd rather keep you as my father than my partner.
那就說出來!
Then say it.
如果你有話要說 我希望你自己開口...
If you've got something to say to me, then say it.
我想聽你說
I'd like to hear you speak...
不想你身後的那條狗叫
instead of your little dog.
我要和妻子一起去墨西哥
I'm going to Mexico with my wife.
我要離開你
I'm going away from you.
看來這不難 是不是?
That wasn't so hard, was it?
你所做的會毀了我們兩個
Killing us with what you're doing.
你正在扼殺我心目中的好兒子形象
You're killing my image of you as my son.
你太固執了 聽不進別人的建議
You are stubborn. You won't listen.
你不是我的兒子
You're not my son.
請別那樣說 我知道你是隨口說說
Please don't say that. I know you don't mean it.
這是事實 你不是我的兒子
It's the truth. You're not my son.
從來都不是
You never have been.
你是一個孤兒
You're an orphan!
聽說過這個詞麼?
Did you ever hear that word?
把我的話告訴他
Tell him what I said.
你今天所作的 和你的身份蠻配
You operated here today like one.
我早該想到有這一天
I should have seen this coming.
我早該知道
I should have known that,
經過了這麼多年...
under this all, these past years
你對我的怨氣一點點積累 最後變成了新的仇恨
you've been building new hate for me piece by piece.
我甚至都不知道你是誰
I don't even know who you are...
你身上根本沒我的影子
because you have none of me in you.
你是別人的孩子
You're someone else's.
你的憤怒 你的怨意
This anger. Your maliciousness.
還有你對我的消極態度...
Backwards dealings with me.
你是裝在籃子裏的孤兒
You're an orphan from a basket...
是我從沙漠中撿來的...
in the middle of the desert.
收養你不為別的
And I took you for no other reason...
只為買地時 身邊有張俏臉蛋 誆人容易些
than I needed a sweet face to buy land.
你聽見沒有?
Did you get that?
現在你總算知道真相了
So now you know.
看著我! 你比爛貨更下賤
Look at me! You're lower than a bastard.
在你體內根本沒有我的血
You have none of me in you.
你不過是籃子裏裝的小爛貨
You're just a bastard from a basket.
感謝主 我體內沒有你的血
I thank God I have none of you in me.
你不是我兒子 只是個不起眼的對手
Not my son. Just a little piece of competition.
籃子裏的爛貨
Bastard from a basket.
籃子裏的爛貨!
Bastard from a basket!
你是籃子裏的爛貨!
You're a bastard from a basket!
起來 丹尼爾先生
Get up, Mr. Daniel.
丹尼爾先生
Mr. Daniel.
丹尼爾先生 有人來拜訪
Mr. Daniel, you've got a visitor.
醒醒 丹尼爾先生
Wake up, Mr. Daniel.
先生?
Sir?
你可以走了
You can leave us now.
丹尼爾
Daniel.
丹尼爾·普萊維 房子著火了!
Daniel Plainview, the house is on fire!
丹尼爾兄弟 是我 伊萊
Brother Daniel, it's Eli.
是你 是你啊
Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
來杯酒吧
I'll make us a drink.
你的家真是個奇跡
Your home is a miracle.
太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
願主保佑這裏
God bless it.
這些日子我一直在各地傳道
I've been spreading His word far and wide.
廣為傳道
Far and wide.
為了主我四處奔波
So much travel for Him.
我還曾通過無線電散播福音
I've been working in radio.
發生了那麼多事情...
Yes, so much...So much has been happening.
回來這裏
To be here...
看到你一切都好 我很高興
and find you and see you well is wonderful.
正好有機會 我們敘敘舊
And we have a chance to catch up.
不用了 謝謝你
No. Thank you so much.
我親愛的兄弟
My brother.
丹尼爾 我的兄弟 我們是姻親啊
Daniel, my brother by marriage.
多少年的老朋友...都這麼多年了
We're such old friends. So much time.
經歷了這麼多起起落落...
Things go up, things go down,
至少還有主總在我們身旁
but at least the Lord is always around.
我們有過得意 也有過失意 不是麼?
We've seen ups and downs, haven't we?
你現在失意麼 伊萊?
Are things down for you right now, Eli?
現在沒有
No. No.
但我的確帶來了一個悲傷的消息
But I do come with some sad news.
還記得班迪先生麼?
Perhaps you remember Mr. Bandy?
他老人家已升入天國了
Mr. Bandy has passed on to the Lord.
他活了99歲 願神保佑
He lived to be 99 years old, God bless him.
班迪先生有個孫子
Mr. Bandy has a grandson.
他叫威廉 你見過麼?
Have you met his grandson, William?
威廉班迪是我們最好的兄弟之一...
William Bandy is one of the finest members we have
為第三啟示教會奉獻了很多
at the Church of the Third Revelation.
他很想去好萊塢拍電影
He's eager to come to Hollywood to be in movies.
他長得不錯
He is very good-looking.
我覺得他能紅
And I do think he will have success.
那樣很好嘛
That's wonderful.
要不要我找他談談?
Would you like me to speak with him?
丹尼爾 我問你是否願意...
Daniel, I'm asking if you'd like to have business
和第三啟示教會做筆交易
with the Church of the Third Revelation
在小班迪的那...
in developing this lease...
一千英畝地上鑽井采油
on young Bandy's 1,000-acre tract.
小波士頓的這塊地 我可以給你
I'm offering you to drill
面積非常大
on one of the great...
還沒人開發過!
undeveloped fields of Little Boston.
- 我很高興和你合作 - 你願意?
- I'd be happy to work with you. - You would?
是是 當然 那樣太好了
Yes, yes, of course. That's wonderful.
但我有個條件
But there is one condition for this work.
好吧你說
All right.
我希望你親口跟我說
I'd like you to tell me that...
你是一個冒牌的先知
you are a false prophet.
我希望你親口跟我說 你是
I'd like you to tell me that you are,
而且從來都是個冒牌的先知
and have been a false prophet.
所謂的上帝也不過是迷信
And that God is a superstition.
這是謊言
But that's a lie.
這是謊言 我不能說謊
It's a lie. I cannot say it.
- 什麼時候開始鑽井? - 很快就能開始
- When can we begin to drill? - Very soon.
那多久之後能開始出油呢?
How long will it take to bring in the well?
不會很久的
It shouldn't take long.
我要十萬美金作為簽字費...
I would like a $100,000 signing bonus,
外加先前欠的五千元 還有利息
plus the five that is owed to me with interest.
恩 這樣才公平嘛
That's only fair.
我是一個冒牌的先知 上帝是迷信的產物
I am a false prophet, and God is a superstition.
如果你這麼認為 我就這麼說
If that's what you believe, then I will say it.
- 要用令人信服的語氣說出來 - 丹尼爾...
- Say it like you mean it. - Daniel.
要用你布道的口氣說
Say it like it's your sermon.
不要笑
Don't smile.
我是一個冒牌的先知
I am a false prophet.
- 上帝是迷信的產物 - 何不站起來說?
- God is a superstition. - Why don't you stand up?
把杯子放下
Put your glass down.
我是一個冒牌的先知
I am a false prophet.
- 上帝是迷信的產物 - 伊萊 停一下
- God is a superstition. - Eli, stop.
把這裏想作是你的教堂
Just imagine this is your church here...
面前還坐滿了信徒...
and you have a full congregation, so...
我是一個冒牌的先知 上帝是迷信的產物
I am a false prophet. God is a superstition.
再說一遍
Say it again.
我是一個冒牌的先知 上帝是迷信的產物
I am a false prophet. God is a superstition.
坐在後面的人聽不清楚
They can't hear you at the back.
我是一個冒牌的先知 上帝是迷信的產物
I am a false prophet. God is a superstition.
再說一遍
Say it again.
我是一個冒牌的先知! 上帝是迷信的產物!
I am a false prophet! God is a superstition!
再說一遍
Say it again.
我是一個冒牌的先知! 上帝是迷信的產物!
I am a false prophet! God is a superstition!
那片地方的油已經採完了
Those areas have been drilled.
什麼?
What?
那些地方的油已經採完了
Those areas, they've been drilled.
- 不 沒有 - 是採完了...
- No, they haven't. - Yes, it's...
這就是所謂的抽水效應 伊萊
It's called drainage, Eli.
聽著 那農場周圍的地都是我的
See, I own everything around it,
所以我早把他地下的油給抽乾了
so, of course, I get what's underneath it.
那兒連個采油平台都沒有
But there are no derricks there.
是班迪的地...知道我說哪兒麼?
This is the Bandy tract. Do you understand?
還沒明白過來 伊萊?
Do you understand, Eli?
似乎沒搞清楚的是你 明白沒有?
That's more to the point. Do you understand?
我喝光了你杯子裏的水 我把它喝光了
I drink your water. I drink it up every day.
我每天都在吸班迪地皮底下的聖血
I drink the blood of Lamb from Bandy's tract.
現在你可以坐下了
You can sit down again.
哦 丹尼爾
Daniel.
丹尼爾
求你了
Please.
- 我已經無路可走了 - 我知道
- I am in desperate times. - I know.
- 我需要一個朋友 - 是啊 你當然需要了
- I need a friend. - Yes. Of course, you do.
我犯了罪
I've sinned.
我需要幫助 我是罪人
I need help. I'm a sinner.
我做夢也不曾想
I've let the devil grab hold...
竟讓魔鬼奪了魂
of me in ways I never imagined.
我是個不折不扣的罪人
I'm so full of sin.
上帝有時候會考驗我們 不是麼?
The Lord sometimes challenges us, doesn't He, Eli?
- 哦 丹尼爾 沒錯... - 是啊 他會的
- Yes, He does, Daniel. - Yes, He does.
是的 他考驗了我啊!
Yes, He does!
是啊 他考驗了你!
最近的經濟大危機
He's completely failed to alert me...
他連一聲提醒都沒給我...
to the recent panic in our economy.
- 還有這件事... - 哦 小可憐
- And this... - Oh, dear.
我必須得弄到錢 丹尼爾
I must have this, Daniel.
我必須 非得 一定要弄到錢
I must, I must, I must have this.
我需要這筆錢填補投資黑洞
My investments have...
丹尼爾 我不想煩你
Daniel, I won't bore you,
可要是能抓到主的手乞求幫助 我早去了
but if I could grab the Lord's hand for help I would
但他總是不吭聲...
but He does these things all the time.
故作神秘 讓我們乾等著...
These mysteries that He presents, and while we wait.
乾等著他發話!
While we wait for His word!
因為上帝選中的兄弟不是你 伊萊
Because you're not the chosen brother, Eli.
他選中了你的雙胞胎兄弟 保羅
'Twas Paul who was chosen.
是保羅找到我 告訴我到這兒來
He found me and told me about your land.
你只是個傻子
You're just a fool.
為什麼要提起保羅?
Why are you talking about Paul?
你兄弟沒做到的 我做到了
I did what your brother couldn't.
別跟我說這些
Don't say this to me.
我擊潰了你 打垮了你
I broke you and I beat you.
是保羅他告訴我有你這麼個人
It was Paul told me about you.
他才是先知 他才是智者
He's the prophet. He's the smart one.
他早知道地底下藏著寶藏
He knew what was there
是他找到了我 讓我去把寶藏挖出來
and he found me to take it out of the ground.
你知道最有趣的是什麼? 聽著 聽好了...
Know what the funny thing is? Listen, listen.
我給了他一萬美元 全是現金 事實就是這樣
I paid him $10,000 cash in hand. Just like that.
他現在自己開了家公司
He has his own company now.
小生意蒸蒸日上
Prosperous little business.
旗下三口油井 周入五千美金
Three wells producing, $5,000 a week.
你個大哭包 別哭哭啼啼了 我不想再聽你胡扯
Stop crying, you sniveling ass. Stop your nonsense.
伊萊 其實你只是你兄弟出生時 順帶落出的那個胎盤
You're just the afterbirth, Eli.
- 不 - 從你母親產後的穢物中滑落出來
- No - That slithered out on your mother's filth.
不
No.
他們應該把你裝在玻璃瓶裏
They should've put you in a glass jar
擱置在壁爐架上
on the mantelpiece.
保羅在媽媽身上...
Where were you when Paul...
吸奶的時候 你在哪兒?
was suckling at his mother's teat?
你在哪兒啊?
Where were you?
誰把你養大的 可憐的伊萊? 班迪家的一頭母豬麼?
Who was nursing you, poor Eli? One of Bandy's sows?
那塊地我早就吃乾淨了
That land has been had.
對此你一點辦法也沒有
Nothing you can do about it. It's gone.
- 請你買下這塊地皮吧... - 你輸了
- If you would just take this lease... - You lose.
抽水效應!
Drainage!
知道抽水效應麼 伊萊! 你個小毛孩子...
Drainage, Eli, you boy.
我很抱歉 已經抽乾了
Drained dry. I'm so sorry.
如果你有一杯奶昔
If you have a milkshake
我也有一杯奶昔...
and I have a milkshake,
我還有一根吸管 就在那兒
and I have a straw, there it is.
那是一根吸管 看到沒?
That's the straw, you see?
看好了
Watch it.
我的吸管穿過房間...
Now my straw reaches across the room
然後開始喝你的奶昔
and starts to drink your milkshake.
我在喝你的奶昔!
I drink your milkshake!
- 我把它喝光了! - 丹尼爾 別逼我
- I drink it up! - Don't bully me, Daniel.
就你那破嗓子和爛舞步
Did you think your song and dance...
還有你那點迷信就能無往不勝麼 伊萊?
and your superstition would help you, Eli?
我才是第三啟示!
I am the Third Revelation.
我才是上帝選中的使者!
I am who the Lord has chosen.
- 丹尼爾! - 因為我比你聰明!
- Daniel! - Because I'm smarter than you!
我比你年長!
I'm older!
我是你的老朋友呀 丹尼爾!
I'm your old friend, Daniel!
- 我可不是什麼假先知... - 救命! 救命啊!
- I'm not a false prophet... - Help me! Help me!
...你這乳臭未乾的娃娃!
...you sniveling boy!
我就是第三啟示!
I am the Third Revelation!
- 我說過要生吃了你! - 我們是親人!
- I told you I would eat you. - We're family!
我說過要生吞了你!
I told you I would eat you up!
我們是兄弟! 是兄弟!
We're brothers! We're brothers!
丹尼爾 請饒了我吧 求你了
Daniel, please forgive me. I beg you.
在那兒 在那兒啊
That's it. That's it.
丹尼爾先生?
Mr. Daniel?
我沒事了
I'm finished.